iniz.com 2019-02-14

# Privacy Policy & GDPR Compliance - INIZ

**GDPR - General Data Protection Regulation  
** If you are a resident of the EEA, we comply in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), this also means our customers must also meet their own regulatory obligations. Please see the relevant sections below which includes the Data Processing Agreement. 

**What information do we collect?  
** We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order or subscribe to our newsletter.

Any data we request that is not required will be specified as voluntary or optional.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address, mailing address or phone number. In addition, we may also collect other identifiable information such as but not limited to your IP, PayPal ID or your oAuth tokens for external sign-in integration. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

**What do we use your information for?  
**Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

\- To process transactions   
Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of processing and delivering the purchased product or service requested by the customer. To process your order we may cross check your details on fraud detection services such as MaxMind & FraudRecord, should you severely violate our terms/aup you may be reported to said services. 

\- To send periodic emails   
The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order or request, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, promotions, related product or service information, etc.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

\- To provide live customer support   
We use tawk.to to provide live chat support and your details (name/email address) including the chat history would be saved on Tawk.to for a maximum of 6 months. 

**How do we protect your information?  
**We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you submit a request, place an order or access your personal information.

These security measures include: password protected directories and databases to safeguard your information or SSL (Secure Sockets Layered) technology to ensure that your information is fully encrypted and sent across the Internet securely.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorised with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.

**Do we use cookies?  
**Yes (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognise your browser and capture and remember certain information.

**Do we disclose any information to outside parties?  
**We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Terms and Conditions  
**Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website and/or services at here.

**GDPR - Personal Information & Your Rights  
**We will retain customer information for at least 24 months after your last account activity, we then may on request remove your details from our public client area (my.iniz.com). We are however obliged to store some of your personal information and transactional data for a minimum of 6 years under the UK regulation however such data is not accessible by customers and hosted off-site.

You may unsubscribe from any marketing emails we may send you from the client area at any time.

If you are a resident of the EEA, you have the following data protection rights:

  * Right of access - You have the right to access your personal data and can request this from us by submitting ticket to escalation.
  * Right to rectification - You have the right to have any incorrect/incomplete personal data corrected.
  * Right to erasure - You have the right to request erasure of your personal data we hold. However the above retention period remains the same and we must oblige with financial and legal obligations to keep certain data such as financial records (eg. invoices) indefinitely. 
  * Right to restrict - You have the right to request the restriction of processing your data where we have no legitimate reason to do so.
  * Right to object - You have the right to object to us processing your personal data where we have no legitimate reason to do so.

**GDPR - Data Processing Agreement  
** By agreeing to our Terms and using our products or services you automatically accept our DPA which can be viewed [here](https://iniz.com/DPA.pdf). 

**GDPR - Data Protection Officer    
**We have appointed a Data Protection Officer. This person is responsible for all privacy related matters in our organization. In case of requests or queries our Data Protection Officer can be reached by email on [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1a7f69797b767b6e7375745a7374736034797577).

**Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance  
** We will not intentionally collect any information from anyone under 16 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 16 years old or older.

**Your Consent  
** By using our site and/or services, you consent to our privacy policy.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy  
**You can review the most current version of the privacy policy at any time at this page. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to update, change or replace any part of these privacy policies by posting updates and changes to our website. It is your responsibility to check our website periodically for changes. Your continued use of or access to our website or the Service following the posting of any changes to these privacy policies constitutes acceptance of those changes.

**Contact Us**   
If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7d1c191014133d14131407531e1210).

Last Updated: 25th October 2018.
